<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMDK on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/tags/pmdk/</link><description>Recent content in PMDK on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/tags/pmdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Disaggregated Memory - In pursuit of scale and efficiency</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</guid><description>A software person perspective on new upcoming interconnect technologies.
Existing Server Landscape Servers are expensive. And difficult to maintain properly. That&amp;rsquo;s why most people turn to the public cloud for their hosting and computing needs. Dynamic virtual server instances have been key to unlocking efficiency gains for both Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and their users. CSPs can leverage virtualization to colocate many workloads on fewer physical servers. And cloud users have access to a huge pool of on-demand processing power, only having to pay for what they use.</description></item><item><title>What is PMDK (Persistent Memory Development Kit)?</title><link>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000009-what-is-pmdk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000009-what-is-pmdk/</guid><description>Answer The Persistent Memory Development Kit (PMDK), formerly known as the Non-Volatile Memory Library (NVML), is a collection of libraries and tools designed to support development of persistent-memory-aware applications. The open source PMDK project currently supports ten libraries, which are targeted at various use cases for persistent memory with language support for C, C++, Java*, and Python*. The PMDK also includes tools like the pmemcheck plug-in for the open source toolset, valgrind, and an increasing body of documentation, code examples, tutorials, and blog entries.</description></item><item><title>What programming languages does PMDK (Persistent Memory Development Kit) support?</title><link>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000011-what-languages-does-pmdk-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000011-what-languages-does-pmdk-support/</guid><description>Answer The Persistent Memory Development Kit (PMDK) core libraries provide C APIs. Libraries such as libpmemobj provide C++ APIs. Higher level libraries such as libpmemkv, a key-value store for persistent memory, support C, C++, Javascript, Java, Ruby, and Python.</description></item><item><title>Why use PMDK (Persistent Memory Development Kit)?</title><link>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000010-why-use-pmdk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/knowledgebase/faq/100000010-why-use-pmdk/</guid><description>Answer The Persistent Memory Development Kit (PMDK) is designed to solve persistent memory challenges and facilitate the adoption of persistent memory programming. It offers developers well-tested, production-ready libraries and tools in a comprehensive implementation of the Storage Networking Industry Association Non-Volatile Memory (SNIA NVM) programming model.</description></item></channel></rss>