<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Memkind on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/tags/memkind/</link><description>Recent content in Memkind on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/tags/memkind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Memory Tiering (part 1)</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-1/</guid><description>Extending memory capacity with PMEM Databases such as Redis (an in-memory key-value open-source database) consume a lot of memory. Since fast access is essential for them, they use DRAM to store their data. DRAM is quite expensive and has limited capacity, so a solution we propose in this blog post is to use PMEM (and in the future other types of memory available through CXL - see a pmem.io blog post about it).</description></item><item><title>Disaggregated Memory - In pursuit of scale and efficiency</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</guid><description>A software person perspective on new upcoming interconnect technologies.
Existing Server Landscape Servers are expensive. And difficult to maintain properly. That&amp;rsquo;s why most people turn to the public cloud for their hosting and computing needs. Dynamic virtual server instances have been key to unlocking efficiency gains for both Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and their users. CSPs can leverage virtualization to colocate many workloads on fewer physical servers. And cloud users have access to a huge pool of on-demand processing power, only having to pay for what they use.</description></item></channel></rss>