<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Memkind on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/tags/memkind/</link><description>Recent content in Memkind on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 13:46:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/tags/memkind/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring the Software Ecosystem for Compute Express Link (CXL) Memory</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2023/05/exploring-the-software-ecosystem-for-compute-express-link-cxl-memory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 13:46:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2023/05/exploring-the-software-ecosystem-for-compute-express-link-cxl-memory/</guid><description>CXL Software ecosystem The Compute Express Link (CXL) is going to be a transformative new technology in the heterogeneous memory space. While the transition from Persistent Memory (PMem) to CXL.mem may seem challenging at first, developers who have optimized their applications for PMem will find that no significant changes may be required. In this article, we will explore the CXL software ecosystem and its compatibility with the established PMem concepts and libraries.</description></item><item><title>Dockers usage in PMDK</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/12/dockers-usage-in-pmdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/12/dockers-usage-in-pmdk/</guid><description>In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe why we believe dockers are easy to use, time-saving, and valuable for day-to-day programming and debugging. If you have never heard of dockers (or containers in general), please read, for example, this overview. We use dockers in almost all of the repositories in our organization. In this blog post, I will describe how we use dockers based on the PMDK repository. In some of our repositories, like in memkind, we use a bit different approach, but it still relies on docker.</description></item><item><title>Memory Tiering (part 1)</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-1/</guid><description>Extending memory capacity with PMEM Databases such as Redis (an in-memory key-value open-source database) consume a lot of memory. Since fast access is essential for them, they use DRAM to store their data. DRAM is quite expensive and has limited capacity, so a solution we propose in this blog post is to use PMEM (and in the future other types of memory available through CXL - see a pmem.io blog post about it).</description></item><item><title>Disaggregated Memory - In pursuit of scale and efficiency</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</guid><description>A software person perspective on new upcoming interconnect technologies.
Existing Server Landscape Servers are expensive. And difficult to maintain properly. That&amp;rsquo;s why most people turn to the public cloud for their hosting and computing needs. Dynamic virtual server instances have been key to unlocking efficiency gains for both Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and their users. CSPs can leverage virtualization to colocate many workloads on fewer physical servers. And cloud users have access to a huge pool of on-demand processing power, only having to pay for what they use.</description></item></channel></rss>