<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>librpma | PMDK on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/rpma/</link><description>Recent content in librpma | PMDK on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/rpma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic - Direct write to PMem | RPMA</title><link>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/basic-direct-write-to-pmem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/basic-direct-write-to-pmem/</guid><description>Direct Write to PMem Direct Write to PMem is a readiness of hardware and software configuration which allows effectively and persistently write data to PMem physically attached to one system from another system using RDMA-capable network. How to achieve Direct Write to PMem capability may differs from system to system because of variety of potential ‘interruptions’ (e.g. caching) in data’s way to be stored persistently on PMem.
2nd Generation Intel® Xeon® Scalable Processors For the 2nd Generation Intel® Xeon® Scalable Processors (Cascade Lake) the only configuration item one should take care of is Intel® Data Direct I/O Technology (DDIO).</description></item><item><title>Basic - HW &amp; SW setup starting point | RPMA</title><link>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/basic-hw_sw_setup_starting_point/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/basic-hw_sw_setup_starting_point/</guid><description>HW &amp;amp; SW setup starting point description In order to make the optimal use of your Remote Persistent Memory:
Make sure you have all following required HW components [1] and check: how many and what kind of those items do you have? Which socket/slot/channel are they located in?:
main system board supporting 2nd generation Intel® Xeon® Scalable processors, 2nd generation Intel® Xeon® Scalable CPUs, Intel® Optane™ persistent memory modules, DRAM DIMMs and RDMA-capable NICs Verify that you have the required Linux kernel version: the Linux NVDIMM/PMem drivers are enabled by default, starting with Linux mainline kernel 4.</description></item><item><title>Performance - Tuning | RPMA</title><link>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/perf-tuning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/rpma/documentation/perf-tuning/</guid><description>Performance - Tuning A collection of the best methods, practices, and configuration values known for delivering the best possible performance in a consistent and predictable way for the workloads built on the librpma library.
General notes The Performance - Tuning aims to collect all tested and proven procedures with known beneficial effects on the performance of the workloads built on the librpma library. Nonetheless, each change of configuration should be set up and tested in a testing environment before being applied to a production system.</description></item></channel></rss>