<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CXL on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/tags/cxl/</link><description>Recent content in CXL on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 13:46:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/tags/cxl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring the Software Ecosystem for Compute Express Link (CXL) Memory</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2023/05/exploring-the-software-ecosystem-for-compute-express-link-cxl-memory/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 13:46:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2023/05/exploring-the-software-ecosystem-for-compute-express-link-cxl-memory/</guid><description>CXL Software ecosystem The Compute Express Link (CXL) is going to be a transformative new technology in the heterogeneous memory space. While the transition from Persistent Memory (PMem) to CXL.mem may seem challenging at first, developers who have optimized their applications for PMem will find that no significant changes may be required. In this article, we will explore the CXL software ecosystem and its compatibility with the established PMem concepts and libraries.</description></item><item><title>Update on PMDK and our long term support strategy</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/11/update-on-pmdk-and-our-long-term-support-strategy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/11/update-on-pmdk-and-our-long-term-support-strategy/</guid><description>Following Intel’s Q2 earnings call announcing the wind-down of Intel’s Optane business, Intel will also be winding down its investment in new feature development on Persistent Memory Development Kit (PMDK) libraries and adjusting long-term support and maintenance plans accordingly.
The PMDK collection of open-source libraries and tools hosted on GitHub will continue to be available to the software community. Documentation and resources via the pmem.io website will also remain available.</description></item><item><title>Memory Tiering (part 2): Writing Transparent Tiering Solution</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-2-writing-transparent-tiering-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-2-writing-transparent-tiering-solution/</guid><description>This is the second part of the series of articles about memory tiering. The first one explained what memory tiering is and why we need it, the second one will explain some mechanisms behind transparent tiering.
This article is intended for those who would like to learn how tiering/numa balancing or memory profiling solutions work under the hood. We will focus on a high-level overview of how tiering/numa balancing could be designed, instead of dissecting any particular solution.</description></item><item><title>Disaggregated Memory - In pursuit of scale and efficiency</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</guid><description>A software person perspective on new upcoming interconnect technologies.
Existing Server Landscape Servers are expensive. And difficult to maintain properly. That&amp;rsquo;s why most people turn to the public cloud for their hosting and computing needs. Dynamic virtual server instances have been key to unlocking efficiency gains for both Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and their users. CSPs can leverage virtualization to colocate many workloads on fewer physical servers. And cloud users have access to a huge pool of on-demand processing power, only having to pay for what they use.</description></item></channel></rss>