<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CXL on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/tags/cxl/</link><description>Recent content in CXL on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/tags/cxl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Memory Tiering (part 2): Writing Transparent Tiering Solution</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-2-writing-transparent-tiering-solution/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/06/memory-tiering-part-2-writing-transparent-tiering-solution/</guid><description>This is the second part of the series of articles about memory tiering. The first one explained what memory tiering is and why we need it, the second one will explain some mechanisms behind transparent tiering.
This article is intended for those who would like to learn how tiering/numa balancing or memory profiling solutions work under the hood. We will focus on a high-level overview of how tiering/numa balancing could be designed, instead of dissecting any particular solution.</description></item><item><title>Disaggregated Memory - In pursuit of scale and efficiency</title><link>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/blog/2022/01/disaggregated-memory-in-pursuit-of-scale-and-efficiency/</guid><description>A software person perspective on new upcoming interconnect technologies.
Existing Server Landscape Servers are expensive. And difficult to maintain properly. That&amp;rsquo;s why most people turn to the public cloud for their hosting and computing needs. Dynamic virtual server instances have been key to unlocking efficiency gains for both Cloud Service Providers (CSPs) and their users. CSPs can leverage virtualization to colocate many workloads on fewer physical servers. And cloud users have access to a huge pool of on-demand processing power, only having to pay for what they use.</description></item></channel></rss>