<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PMDK on PMem.io</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/pmdk/</link><description>Recent content in PMDK on PMem.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pmem.io/events/pmdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2021 SPDK,PMDK, &amp; Performance Virtual Forum</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/2021-spdk-pmdk-intel-performance-analyzers-virtual-forum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/events/2021-spdk-pmdk-intel-performance-analyzers-virtual-forum/</guid><description>Thank you all for attending the SPDK, PMDK and Intel® Performance Analyzers Virtual Forum. We had a very successful Virtual Forum this year with awesome content and presenters. You can download the presentations using the links below. Please note these are static PDFs, but many of the presentations made extensive use of animations, so something may be lost in translation.
The videos are available in the SPDK 2021 US Virtual Forum YouTube Channel.</description></item><item><title>2020 PRC SPDK,PMDK, &amp; Performance Virtual Forum</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/2020-prc-spdk-pmdk-intel-performance-analyzers-virtual-forum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/events/2020-prc-spdk-pmdk-intel-performance-analyzers-virtual-forum/</guid><description>Thank you all for attending the 2020 PRC SPDK, PMDK and Intel® VTune™ Profiler Virtual Forum. We had a very successful Virtual Forum this year with awesome content and presenters. You can download the presentations using the links below. Please note these are static PDFs, but many of the presentations made extensive use of animations, so something may be lost in translation.
The videos will be available in our YouTube channel.</description></item><item><title>SPDK,PMDK,and Intel VTune Summit 2020</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-2020/</guid><description>Thank you all for attending the 2020 PRC SPDK, PMDK and Intel® VTune™ Profiler Virtual Forum. We had a very successful Virtual Forum this year with awesome content and presenters. You can download the presentations using the links below. Please note these are static PDFs, but many of the presentations made extensive use of animations, so something may be lost in translation.
The videos are available on the SPDK 2020 US Virtual Forum YouTube Channel.</description></item><item><title>SPDK PMDK and Intel VTune Summit PRC 2019</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-prc-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-prc-2019/</guid><description>Thank you all for attending the SPDK, PMDK and Intel® VTune™ Amplifier PRC Summit. We had a very successful summit this year with awesome content and presenters. You can download the presentations including opening, keynotes, technical sessions and hands on labs using the links below. Please note these are static PDFs, but many of the presentations made extensive use of animations, so something may be lost in translation.
Videos Watch the recordings of this event on the SPDK 2019 PRC Summit YouTube Channel.</description></item><item><title>SPDK,PMDK, &amp; VTune Summit 2019</title><link>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pmem.io/events/spdk-pmdk-and-intel-vtune-summit-2019/</guid><description>Thank you all for attending the SPDK, PMDK and Intel® VTune™ Amplifier Summit. We had a very successful SPDK summit this year with awesome content and presenters. You can download the presentations using the links below. Please note these are static PDFs, but many of the presentations made extensive use of animations, so something may be lost in translation.
Videos The recordings from the event can be replayed on Youtube -SPDK Track 2019</description></item></channel></rss>